Privacy Policy
==============

What is Gyroscope?
------------------

Gyroscope is a dashboard to help you track and improve everything about your life. It is powered by data from your phone, wearables and other connected accounts, so you rarely have to manually enter data.

The entire purpose of the service is to process and store information for you, much of which occurs on our servers. Most of our users find the health improvements and other benefits from the service far outweigh the slight reduction in privacy. However, if you are not comfortable with us processing and storing your information, then you should not use the service or send us any data.

### TLDR:

Your privacy is critically important to us. At Gyroscope, we have a few fundamental principles:

* Your account is completely private by default.
* You can add as much or as little data as you want.
* You can delete your account and data at any time.
* We are very protective of our user’s data and privacy.
* It is easy to share your profile with friends or the public, but you do not have to.
* Information you post or sync may be seen by others depending on your settings.
* The Vault (a premium feature) lets you enter more advanced data, like blood sugar or DNA, and ensures that they can not be seen by anyone else on Gyroscope.
* We do not sell your data, and only make money from people paying us directly.
* We do automatic tracking and syncing in the background as much as possible, so you do not have to do a lot of work to maintain your account and manually enter data every day.
* Aggregate information may be used for research, quality assurance, and improving the Gyroscope service—for example, using all of the sleep data to improve the accuracy of our automatic sleep detection (a free feature which anyone can use, by the way), or analyzing when people get sick to prevent our users from getting sick in the future.
* Connecting a 3rd party service gives us access to that data, but does not send your Gyroscope info to them. It is a one way connection. For example, if you connect Facebook, that gives us access to sync your profile photo and basic info, but does not give Facebook access to any of your Gyroscope data. With this in mind, we recommend people use Facebook login for the most easy signup experience, and to prevent the hassle of forgotten passwords. This does not reduce the privacy or security of your account in any way.

Who We Are
----------

We are Gyroscope Innovations, Inc. (collectively referred to herein as "Gyroscope," "we," "us," or "our"). We provide Internet and mobile app-based services including, for example, the apps listed below ("Mobile Apps" or "Apps"):

* Gyroscope Annual Report books

BY USING THE SERVICES, YOU CONSENT TO THE COLLECTION, USE AND TRANSFER OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA FOR PROCESSING IN THE UNITED STATES AS DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY.

In order to comply with the requirements of the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) for our European consumers and users, this Privacy Policy outlines the legal basis on which we process your Personal Data and provides other information required by the GDPR.

Information About Your Personal Data
------------------------------------

This Privacy Policy relates to data about you, your devices, and your interaction with our Services.  

"Personal Data" is information that can be used to identify you, directly or indirectly, alone or together with other information. This includes things such as your full name, email address, phone number, precise location, device IDs, certain cookie and network identifiers, and "Fitness and Wellness Data."

Gyroscope collects, uses, discloses and processes Personal Data as outlined in this Privacy Policy, including to operate and improve the Services and our business; for advertising and marketing; and to provide you with innovative fitness and wellness services, as further described in this Privacy Policy.  

We may create aggregated, de-identified or anonymous data from Personal Data by excluding data components (such as your name, email address, or linkable tracking ID) that makes the data personally identifiable to you, through obfuscation, or through other means. Our use of anonymized and de-identified data is not subject to this Privacy Policy. 

How to Contact Us
-----------------

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about how we handle your Personal Data, then you may contact us by sending a message to support@gyrosco.pe

Privacy Settings
----------------

Within our Services there are two sharing settings: Private, and Public. Gyroscope apps are designed for your wellness and fitness benefit. As such, you are able to control what Personal Data you share and with whom you share it.

Adding friends on the service will allow them to see your private profile. Not approving friends and keeping your account private will keep your account completely private.

We encourage you to adjust the sharing settings to best meet your objectives and sharing comfort level.

Deleting Information and Accounts
---------------------------------

You may delete your account at any time by visiting [https://gyrosco.pe/delete](https://gyrosco.pe/delete/). Once deleted, your data, including your account, username, or any other related content, cannot be restored.

Note that content you have shared with others (for example, through saving photos), exported from the service, or that others have copied may also remain visible after you have deleted your account or deleted the information from your own profile. Your public profile may be displayed in search engine results until the search engine refreshes its cache.

What information do we collect?
-------------------------------

When you sign up for an account, we start building your profile and adding data to it. A basic user account has details like your name, email address, profile photo, cover photo, date of birth, and gender. These can be prefilled by Facebook login, or manually entered.

The Gyroscope app tracks some basic stats like steps and sleep, but it is mostly powered by the other services and devices you connect to it. We have many integrations and are constantly adding more. We will update this list as the data we collect evolves. The more services you connect to your account, the more data you will be able to see on your profile and in the app. What you feel comfortable connecting and sharing is up to you.

Each type of account has different content and various amounts of personally-identifiable information, so you may be comfortable with connecting some and not others. For example, you might be comfortable connecting your public photos from Instagram, but not the locations you've been to on Foursquare.

We use our access to your accounts only to load the information we need, never to write or modify your data in any way. For example, if you connect your Twitter account we will never post anything on your behalf. In most cases, we only ask for read-only access to your accounts.

We load data once when your account is first connected, and then periodically to keep your account up to date. This data is processed and stored on Gyroscope servers so it can be accessed through the website, mobile app and other platforms. When you disconnect an account, we also delete all of the associated data that was imported from that account.

The following are some of the commonly used services we integrate with, and the data that can come from it.

### Steps

We load your count of daily steps from a variety of sources. You can select which is the primary source in settings. The common sources for steps include Apple Health, Google Fit, Fitbit, Garmin, and others.

### HealthKit

From the iPhone app, we load various data-points from HealthKit (aka Apple Health) during the initial install, and keep them synced occasionally throughout the day. When installing the app, you will be able to choose which data types you want to sync. The possible options include: steps, workouts, sleep, heart rate, weight, bodyfat percentage, blood pressure, blood glucose, and menstrual cycles. Pro users can also use details like calories, carbs/protein/fat intake, mindfulness time, and more if it is available in HealthKit.

Setting up Gyroscope syncing will upload the data from your phone to our servers.

### Runkeeper, Strava, Moves

Runs, swims, walks, biking and other types of physical activity. The details we get include the start time, duration, pace, calories, etc. If available, we also load the latitude/longitude coordinates to plot it on a map. We also load your heart rate information if available.

### Withings/Nokia

We sync with Withings to retreive bodyweight measurements taken with their wireless scales. We also load blood pressure and heart rates. If you use the Withings sleep tracker, we also load your sleep data.

### Moves, Foursquare

We load a list of the places you've been to. From Moves, these contain Foursquare or Facebook locations and the start and end times. From Foursquare, these consist of checkins at a point in time. These can contain latitude/longitude coordinates and addresses of locations. If both Moves and Foursquare are connected at the same time, we prioritize the data from Moves because it has more details about the time spent—for example that you were at a restaurant for an hour and a half, rather than just that you were there at a specific time of day. From Foursquare, we may also load photos that were associated with your checkins.

### RescueTime

We use RescueTime to calculate your productivity for each day and show your top apps and websites. We load an hourly list of what apps and websites you used. Pages visited in incognito mode are not tracked by RescueTime and not loaded by us. We understand that this data is potentially very sensitive, and only show basic averages of productivity and a few of the top apps, and not individual websites or applications.

### Twitter

We connect to Twitter to load your latest shared photos. We look at the favorite counts to feature the top photos you've shared on Twitter. We get read-only access and never will write to your Twitter—we only use it to get your latest shared content.

### Google Fit

Especially for users on the Android platform, we use Google Fit to load stats like step counts and heart rate.

### Instagram

Similar to Twitter, we connect to Instagram to load all of the photos you have posted. This happens whether or not the Instagram account was set to private, so if you don't want to load your Instagram photos it is recommended to not connect your account.

### 23&me

Pro members can upload an export of their 23&me data, and we will load relevant reports to show in the Vault. These include stats like your muscle fiber composition, lactose intolerance, and other simple traits. The raw data is stored for further analysis and correlation, and tailoring your Gyroscope experience in the future. Once you have added the DNA integration, you can always delete it through the website later. The DNA stats are only accessible by you in the Vault, and not shared with friends or visible on your profile. DNA data can be deleted at any time from the Vault.

### Manually entered data

In addition to the integrations, info can be manually entered into Gyroscope.

Members can take a simple quiz in the app to track their mood, and also manually enter other details like symptoms, sport injuries, and blood sugar measurements or ketone levels for those on a ketogenic diet. These are only for your own easy reference, and potential corellations in the future, and should not be considered medical data.

Gyroscope cannot provide any medical recommendations or analysis of your medical data, and you should always consult with your doctor before making any changes to your behavior or following anything that the app may suggest.

Data stored in the Vault will remain private and not be revealed to any friends. However, it may be used to find correlations or for large-scale studies in aggregate across the platform — ie. researching why users get sick or how to prevent injuries.

### Saved Cards

Cards from the mobile app can be added to your account via the Saved Cards feature. When saving a card to share, you can also add it to your friends feed which will make it viewable by your friends and coworkers on Gyroscope.

Cards that are saved to your saved cards are part of your profile and can be viewed in the app, and by your friends. An image an be removed right after it is added, or at any time later with the delete button in your highlights tab.

Cards from all your friends can be aggregated and shown in a feed, for motivating your friends and allowing liking/commenting. If you like or comment on someone's card, they may be notified about it.

### Payments

We offer free and paid accounts. Those who upgrade to Gyroscope Track, Pro, Score, XRAY, Coach or other premium subscriptions will be charged a recurring fee, depending on the plan selected. Durations can range from monthly to yearly. Refunds will not be granted.

Through the website, you can upgrade with Stripe Checkout. In the app, you can upgrade with In App Purchase. You get the same features, on all platforms, but are just charged in different ways.

Upgrades done on the website use Stripe to store credit cards and do recurring billing. Credit card details are stored entirely by Stripe and not by Gyroscope. We only store a token linked to that credit card, and none of your actual credit card information. If you subscribed with Stripe and entered your credit card, you can manage your subscription or edit your card information from the [billing page](https://gyrosco.pe/billing/)

Subscriptions through iTunes can be managed through your Apple ID — [Learn more about iTunes subscriptions.](https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202039)

Subscriptions through the Google Play Store can be managed in the Google Play Store settings — [Learn more about Google Play subscriptions.](https://support.google.com/googleplay/answer/7018481?co=GENIE.Platform%3DAndroid&hl=en)

### In App Purchases with mobile app

Gyroscope memberships can be purchased directly with card on the website, or subscribed through the iPhone and Android apps.

You can do monthly or yearly subscription, and the exact price will depend on your App Store region—since the prices are converted to local currency in different places. In the US, the price is $9.99/month or $69.99/year with the annual discount

Payment will be charged to iTunes Account or Google Play account at confirmation of purchase. Subscription automatically renews unless auto-renew is turned off at least 24-hours before the end of the current period. Account will be charged for renewal within 24-hours prior to the end of the current period.

Subscriptions may be managed by the user and auto-renewal may be turned off by going to iTunes or Google Play subscription settings after purchase.

### Cookies

These are required to log in to your account and for basic web browsing features. When you visit the Services, a cookie will be stored on your computer.

### Log Files

The Services use log files. Stored information includes IP addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. This information is used to analyze trends, administer, protect and secure the Services, track member movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. These files may be stored on our servers or on analytics platforms that we use.

Who can see your content?
-------------------------

By default, your account is set to private and you are the only one who can see your profile. Everyone else will see a screen with your profile photo, name, and the fact that your account is private and you must be friends to view the page.

There are two simple visibility options: Private (Friends only) or Public.

The default is Friends Only, and you will have no friends until you accept some requests or send requests to add people, so your account starts off as completely private.

If people add you as a friend (and you accept), or you request that someone be your friend, they will be able to see your profile and all your weekly reports. Be careful when adding friends on Gyroscope, and only accept people that you know and trust. If you do not wish to give them access to view your complete Gyroscope profile, then you should not accept their friend request.

That said, some people (including everyone on the Gyroscope team) may choose to make their page completely public and transparently share it with the world. We have designed most of the views Gyroscope with this in mind, to analyze and share your stats in a way that is not embarassing or dangerous. Public profiles can be viewed by anyone, and may occasionally be featured on our homepage and other parts of Gyroscope.

Gyroscope staff can also view your profile for testing or support purposes, but will never share anything not made public.

We only use your data to power your profile page, and will never share or sell your details to any 3rd parties. Data in your account can also be used to order print goods like posters and books for your own personal usage, which may require more access by Gyroscope staff to generate.

### Hiding options

If you don’t want a constant reminder of your age or weight, you can choose to hide them from settings. That will put them "out of sight & out of mind" but isn't intended to make them completely inaccessible. Hiding in settings isn’t a guarantee that the data is gone, but just a preference to not show it prominently and remind you about it.

### The Vault

A Pro feature called the Vault gives you additional granularity over what gets shared. For example, you can add friends but move your locations or weight to the Vault if you don’t want them to be able to see it. Otherwise by default, adding friends will let them see the same view of your profile as yourself.

The Vault doesn't add encryption or significantly change how the information is stored, but changes the access control to ensure that you have maximum privacy and no other members on the service can access the info. From user research, we've found that the main risk in tracking your weight or productivity is not in some russian adversary gaining access to the data, but being embarassed by it with your friends. The Vault is designed to protect against these scenarios.

Separate from the Vault, all users have the option to hide common things like weight and age from the account settings. Those are common items that people may not want to be reminded of or see on their profile, so we have made those easy to hide.

The difference between hiding something or moving it to the Vault is whether you want to hide it from everyone including yourself, or just from everyone else but keep seeing it yourself. The Vault also allows hiding for other data-types like location and computer usage.

### API Access & exporting

There is currently no public API to get data out of Gyroscope. Your account data can be exported at https://gyrosco.pe/export/

### Your company on Gyroscope

If your company has a Gyroscope membership, you may be able to join your company on Gyroscope. Joining will give you a Pro membership, and it will also give other members in the company access to certain details from your account—including things like your steps or recent workouts. Information stored in the Vault or set to be hidden will still be kept private from other members.

GDPR Details
------------

### How We Collect and Use Personal Data

We collect your Personal Data in a number of ways and for various purposes, including:

1. When you register for an account or interact with our Services.
2. When you input Fitness and Wellness Data within our Services or use our Services that collect or infer such data from mobile device sensors.
3. When you use or interact with a wearable or other connected device.
4. When you give us permission to sync Apple Health data in the iPhone app.
5. When you give us permission to sync Samsung or Google Fit data in the Android app.
6. When you give us permission to collect Location Data in the mobile apps.
7. When you connect an integration to sync data to your account.
8. When you communicate with us or sign up for promotional materials.
9. When you engage with our online communities or advertising.
10. When you access third party products and services.
11. When you connect with us through social media.
12. When we collect data from third parties or publicly-available sources.
13. When we leverage and/or collect cookies, device IDs, Location, data from the environment, and other tracking technologies.
14. When we aggregate or centralize data.
15. When we link you to friends across platforms.
16. When you take fitness tests or assessments; share content or achievements; or invite friends.
17. When we provide you geographically relevant Services, offers, or advertising.
18. When you ask us to customize products, or Services.
19. When we comply with Legal Requirements or Obligations, Law Enforcement, and for Public Safety Purposes ( Country/Region-Specific Disclosures may apply).

### How Information is Shared

We may disclose your Personal Data for the purposes as described in the prior section of this Privacy Policy, and in the following ways:

1. To the public if you set your account to public
2. To people you have approved as friends on Gyroscope
3. To other Users/Gyroscope Registered Users
4. To Affiliates and Partners
5. To Service Providers and Vendors
6. For Advertising and Marketing
7. For Certain Analytics and Improvement 
8. For Interest-Based Advertising
9. For Legal Compliance, Law Enforcement, and Public Safety Purposes
10. In the event of an actual or contemplated sale

### Publicly Available Information

Subject to your privacy settings, some of your information and content may be publicly accessible. Having an account on the service will make your name, profile photo and cover photo viewable so people can send a friend request. More sensitive details like your recent activity will remain private unless made public, or a friend request is accepted.

### Affiliates and Acquirors of our Business or Assets

We may share your information with affiliates under common control with us, who are required to comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy with regard to your information. If Gyroscope becomes involved in a business combination, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, dissolution or other similar transaction, we may share or transfer your information in connection with such transaction.

### Transfers of Your Personal Data to Other Countries

The Personal Data Gyroscope processes, and all associated Services and systems, including registration, is housed on servers in the United States. If you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that Personal Data we collect will be processed and stored in the United States (the data protection and privacy laws in the United States may offer a lower level of protections than in your country/region).  

By using our Services and submitting your Personal Data, you agree to the transfer, storage, and/or processing of your Personal Data in the United States. Where and as required, we will seek your explicit consent as outlined in this Privacy Policy.

European Union rights
---------------------

If you are habitually located in the European Union, you have the right to access, rectify, download or erase your information, as well as the right to restrict and object to certain processing of your information. While some of these rights apply generally, certain rights apply only in certain limited circumstances. We describe these rights below:

### Access and Porting 

You can access much of your information by logging into your account. People in the EU can find export their history as CSVs from [https://gyrosco.pe/export/](https://gyrosco.pe/export/)

### Rectify, Restrict, Limit, Delete

 You can also rectify, restrict, limit or delete much of your information by logging into your account and deleting particular integrations, data points, or the entire account.

### Object 

Where we process your information based on our legitimate interests explained above, or in the public interest, you can object to this processing in certain circumstances. In such cases, we will cease processing your information unless we have compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing or where it is needed for legal reasons. 

### Revoke consent 

Where you have previously provided your consent, such as to permit us to process health-related data about you, you have the right to withdraw your consent to the processing of your information at any time. For example, you can withdraw your consent by updating your settings or disconnecting an integration. In certain cases, we may continue to process your information after you have withdrawn consent if we have a legal basis to do so or if your withdrawal of consent was limited to certain processing activities. 

### Complain

 Should you wish to raise a concern about our use of your information (and without prejudice to any other rights you may have), you have the right to do so with your local supervisory authority. 

Legal Basis for Processing
--------------------------

This section addresses the legal basis for processing your data if you reside outside the United States (within the United States, you typically provide consent when you receive notice of this Privacy Policy in a website link or mobile app). Some processing is addressed in multiple sections because more than one legal basis may apply depending on the circumstances or service. 

For the purposes of applicable data protection laws, Gyroscope Innovations, Inc. is the controller of the Personal Data you provide to us ("Data Controller"). As a Data Controller, we process the Personal Data we maintain about you in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions or concerns regarding the processing of your Personal Data, or if you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please see our Country/Region-Specific Disclosures for appropriate contact information.

We collect and process your Personal Data for a variety of purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy. In certain cases, separate consent is not required, including:  

1. For the performance of a contract
2. To meet legal obligations
3. For Legitimate Interests

Consent as a Basis for Processing
---------------------------------

In some cases, we will ask for your consent to process your Personal Data. You may indicate your consent in a number of ways, including, as permitted by law, ticking a box or connecting an integration, to indicate your consent when (i) providing us with your Personal Data through our Services or a form (including enrolling in Promotions); or (ii) registering or creating an account with us. Due to different countries' laws governing consent for the collection and use of Personal Data, the requirements for consent will differ across regions. We may request your consent for a number of activities including:

1. Gyroscope Marketing and Communication
2. Third Party Marketing
3. Collecting Mobile Device IDs, Advertising IDs, and Data from Sensors
4. Processing Sensitive Personal Data
5. Collecting and Sharing Location Data
6. Research
7. Advertising
8. Transfer of Data
9. Automated Processing
10. To Enable Social Sharing and Connect with Us on Social Media
11. Promotions

### Managing Preferences and Withdrawing Consent

You may at any time withdraw your consent with future effect and without affecting the lawfulness of processing of your Personal Data based on the consent you provided before you withdrew it, and exercise other controls regarding website and online data collection, interest-based advertising, your communication settings, and app preferences. Depending on the Service, collection and use of Personal Data may be required for the Services to work. To withdraw your consent, you can delete your account at gyrosco.pe/delete/ which will stop the future processing of data.

### Interest-Based Advertising

We do very little advertising, and mostly rely on word of mouth for growth. Occasionally we will do advertisments to get more users for the service. Interest-based advertising is advertising that is targeted to you based on your web browsing and app usage over time and across websites or apps.

How We Protect Information
--------------------------

### Data Retention

We will retain your Personal Data for as long as you maintain an account or as otherwise necessary to provide you the Services. Since part of the service is keeping your history for you to view later, we will generally retain data as much as possible. We will also retain your Personal Data as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.  

Where we no longer need to process your Personal Data for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, we will delete your Personal Data from our systems. 

Where permissible, we will also delete your Personal Data upon your request. If you have questions about our data retention practices, please contact us through our Support Team.

### Security

We implement appropriate technical and organizational safeguards to protect against unauthorized or unlawful processing of Personal Data and against accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure of, or access to Personal Data. Please be advised, however, that we cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with the storage and transmission of Personal Data.

Although we strive to employ reasonable protections for your information that are appropriate to its sensitivity, we do not guarantee or warrant the security of the information you share with us and we are not responsible for the theft, destruction, loss or inadvertent disclosure of your information or content.

### Links to Other Websites

Please note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that we do not own or control or to people that we do not employ or manage. Our Services may provide a link, recommendations or otherwise provide access to Third Party Sites. We provide these links merely for your convenience. We have no control over, do not review, and are not responsible for Third Party Sites, their content, or any goods or services available through the Third Party Sites. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to Third Party Sites, and any data you provide to Third Party Sites, you provide at your own risk. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any Third Party Sites with that you interact with.

### Children

We do not knowingly collect Personal Data online from children under 13 (note that the minimum age may vary based on country/region, and on local law). If you become aware that a child has provided us with Personal Data without parental consent, please contact us through our Support Team. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Data without parental consent, we will take steps to remove the data and cancel the child's account.

Privacy Policy Changes
----------------------

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Gyroscope may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, especially as we add new features and improvements to the product.

Gyroscope encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Most changes will be around keeping the details up to date or in updating it to reflect changes in legal reuqirements, and not material changes to how we actually handle your privacy. If we make significant changes, we may send you a notification through email. Your further use of the Services after a change to our Privacy Policy will be subject to the updated policy.

If you object to anything in this Privacy Policy, you should stop using the Services and [delete your account.](https://gyrosco.pe/delete/)

That’s it! Thanks for reading.
